export const COSTINGA2018 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Cost Accounting involves the ascertainment of cost and relating them to",
A: "cost centres and cost units.",
B: "management and employees.",
C: "material cost and labour cost.",
D: "standards and budgets.",
answer: "A. cost centres and cost units.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The objective of setting up a cost centre is to",
A: "control cost.",
B: "determine cost.",
C: "maximize cost,",
D: "reduce cost.",
answer: "A. control cost.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Cost Accounting information will be useful if it is",
A: "complicated.",
B: "economical.",
C: "prepared by management.",
D: "presented on time.",
answer: "D. relevant for the intended purpose",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. For Cost Accounting information to be easily understood by users, it should be",
A: "accurate.",
B: "objective.",
C: "simple.",
D: "reliable.",
answer: "C. simple.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Classification of cost involves the grouping of cost according to common",
A: "characteristics.",
B: "departments.",
C: "sources.",
D: "values.",
answer: "A. characteristics.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Cost which can be identified with a job or product is",
A: "conversion cost.",
B: "functional cost.",
C: "prime cost.",
D: "sunk cost.",
answer: "C. prime cost.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Cost which does not involve cash payment but rather a sacrifice made is",
A: "future cost.",
B: "historical cost.",
C: "imputed cost.",
D: "sunk cost.",
answer: "C. imputed cost.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The summation of material cost, direct wages and factory overheads is",
A: "conversion cost.",
B: "cost of sales.",
C: "production cost.",
D: "total cost.",
answer: "C. production cost.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Keeping too little stocks can lead to",
A: "increase in cost of capital.",
B: "loss of customers.",
C: "high cost of storage.",
D: "loss through evaporation.",
answer: "B. loss of customers.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The method of stocks valuation that minimises fluctuations in profit due to constant price changes is",
A: "FIFO.",
B: "LIFO.",
C: "Simple average.",
D: "Weighted average.",
answer: "B. LIFO.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Cost of sale using weighted average method of stock valuation is",
A: "GH¢ 3,500.",
B: "GH¢ 3,850.",
C: "GH¢ 4,025.",
D: "GH¢ 4,550.",
answer: "C. GH¢ 4,025.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Cost of sale using simple average method of stock valuation is",
A: "GH¢ 3,500.",
B: "GH¢ 3,850.",
C: "GH¢ 4,025.",
D: "GH¢ 4,550.",
answer: "B. GH¢ 3,850.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Value of closing stock using weighted average method is",
A: "GH¢ 2,500.",
B: "GH¢ 2,750.",
C: "GH¢ 2,875.",
D: "GH¢ 3,200.",
answer: "B. GH¢ 2,750.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Periodic stocktaking is ideally conducted",
A: "after every purchase or sale.",
B: "at the close of work everyday.",
C: "at the end of the year.",
D: "continuously throughout the year.",
answer: "C. at the end of the year.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The protection of materials from damage and deterioration is the duty of",
A: "production manager.",
B: "purchases manager.",
C: "stores clerk.",
D: "store keeper.",
answer: "D. store keeper.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Workers are paid GH¢12 per unit produced subject to a minimum wage of GH¢ 4,200 per month The minimum wage of GH¢4,200 is",
A: "guaranteed wage.",
B: "incentive scheme.",
C: "premium bonus.",
D: "overtime premium.",
answer: "A. guaranteed wage.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Sanni basic wage for Week 3 is",
A: "D 1.440.",
B: "D 1.200.",
C: "D 1.152.",
D: "D 960",
answer: "D. D 960",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Overtime premium for Sanni is",
A: "D 288",
B: "D 240",
C: "D 110",
D: "D 48.",
answer: "D. D 48.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Sanni’s total remuneration for Week 3 is",
A: "D 1.440.",
B: "D 1.200.",
C: "D 1.152.",
D: "D 960",
answer: "B. D 1.200.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Which of the following is a statutory deduction in payroll?",
A: "Health insurance",
B: "Provident fund",
C: "Social security",
D: "Welfare dues",
answer: "C. Social security",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Payment to employees for completing work before the time allocated for the work is",
A: "extra allowance.",
B: "guaranteed wages.",
C: "overtime premium.",
D: "premium bonus.",
answer: "D. premium bonus.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Overheads may be absorbed on the basis of",
A: "area occupied.",
B: "direct material cost.",
C: "machine capacity.",
D: "number of employees.",
answer: "C. machine capacity.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Predetermined overhead absorption rate is",
A: "Le 9.00 per labour hour.",
B: "Le 8.27 per labour hour.",
C: "Le 7.65 per labour hour.",
D: "Le 4.14 per labour hour.",
answer: "A. Le 9.00 per labour hour.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Actual overhead absorbed is",
A: "Le 199,800.",
B: "Le 108,000.",
C: "Le 99,900.",
D: "Le 91,800.",
answer: "C. Le 99,900.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Overhead absorbed by Product MX is",
A: "Le 2,250.00",
B: "Le 2,067.50",
C: "Le 1,912.50",
D: "Le 1,035.00",
answer: "B. Le 2,067.50",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The need to complete cost sheet before the end of the accounting period leads to the computation of",
A: "apportioned overheads.",
B: "fixed overheads.",
C: "predetermined overheads.",
D: "variable overheads.",
answer: "C. predetermined overheads.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Activity based costing assigns cost to products and services based on activity centres called",
A: "cost centres.",
B: "cost drivers.",
C: "cost units.",
D: "cost pools.",
answer: "B. cost drivers.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Overtime worked at the request of a customer is charged to the job as",
A: "direct labour cost.",
B: "idle time.",
C: "indirect expenses.",
D: "indirect labour cost.",
answer: "A. direct labour cost.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The cost of work certified in a contract is debited to",
A: "Architect’s Account.",
B: "Contractee’s Account.",
C: "Contract Account.",
D: "Profit and Loss Account.",
answer: "C. Contract Account.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Standard costing is used for",
A: "overhead absorption.",
B: "performance evaluation.",
C: "production planning.",
D: "profit determination.",
answer: "B. performance evaluation.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Cost per patient per month is",
A: "Le 200.",
B: "Le 150.",
C: "Le 75.",
D: "Le 5.",
answer: "D. Le 5. ",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Cost per day is",
A: "Le 20,000.",
B: "Le 15,000.",
C: "Le 75.",
D: "Le 5.",
answer: "D. Le 5. ",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Number of patients per day is",
A: "200.",
B: "150.",
C: "134.",
D: "75.",
answer: "C. 134. ",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Fixed cost is charged to the product in",
A: "absorption costing.",
B: "contract costing.",
C: "marginal costing.",
D: "standard costing.",
answer: "A. absorption costing.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. In budgetary control, actual results are compared with",
A: "forecast.",
B: "plan,",
C: "standard.",
D: "variance.",
answer: "B. plan, ",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Which of the following budgets is designed to be implemented over a long period?",
A: "Cash budget",
B: "Sales budget",
C: "Production budget",
D: "Capital expenditure budget",
answer: "D. Capital expenditure budget",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Variable cost per unit is",
A: "D 185.10.",
B: "D 182.40.",
C: "D 180.00.",
D: "D 144.00.",
answer: "C. D 180.00.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Fixed cost is",
A: "144,000.",
B: "D 75,000.",
C: "D 72,000.",
D: "D 500.",
answer: "C. D 72,000.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Break-even point in units is",
A: "558,526 units.",
B: "144,000 units.",
C: "2,880 units.",
D: "144 units.",
answer: "C. 2,880 units.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The principal budget factor is the factor that",
A: "determines the budget period.",
B: "improves production.",
C: "leads to maximization of profit.",
D: "limits the scope of operations.",
answer: "D. limits the scope of operations.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. The sales budget is a statement of planned sales in terms of",
A: "quantity and quality.",
B: "quantity and value.",
C: "quantity only.",
D: "value only.",
answer: "B. quantity and value.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. In the preparation of a cash budget, depreciation on fixed assets is treated",
A: "cash receipt.",
B: "cash payment.",
C: "cash expense.",
D: "non-cash expense.",
answer: "D. non-cash expense.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. An adverse material price variance is paused by the use of",
A: "higher priced materials.",
B: "higher grade materials.",
C: "lower priced materials.",
D: "lower grade materials.",
answer: "A. higher priced materials.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. A standard that makes allowance for normal losses is",
A: "attainable standard.",
B: "basic standard.",
C: "current standard.",
D: "ideal standard.",
answer: "A. attainable standard.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. A factor which causes variances in all standards is",
A: "poor quality materials.",
B: "poor forecasting.",
C: "idle time.",
D: "machine breakdown.",
answer: "B. poor forecasting.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The standard that is designed to be used over several years is",
A: "attainable standard.",
B: "basic standard.",
C: "current standard.",
D: "ideal standard.",
answer: "B. basic standard.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. In setting materials cost standard, it is necessary to specify",
A: "quantity and price.",
B: "quantity and quality.",
C: "quantity and usage.",
D: "quality and price",
answer: "A. quantity and price.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. An item that appears in cost accounts but not financial accounts is",
A: "dividend received.",
B: "imputed cost.",
C: "interest paid.",
D: "loss on sale of asset.",
answer: "B. imputed cost.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The cost of goods produced is obtained in",
A: "Cost of Sales Control Account.",
B: "General Ledger Control Account.",
C: "Production Overhead Control Account.",
D: "Work in Progress Control Account.",
answer: "D. Work in Progress Control Account",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Factory overhead incurred is",
A: "credited to Factory Overhead Account.",
B: "credited to Work in Progress Account.",
C: "debited to Production Overhead Account.",
D: "debited to Work in Progress Account.",
answer: "D. Depreciation of assets.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]